and us in the car today we are going to
talk about AI machine learning and deep
learning the reason why is because AI is
everywhere in the news the government
loves to put money on AI project a pinch
of cube todo investors love to put money
on machine learning powered companies
investment and everybody's talking about
deep learning algorithms we are going to
define what is AI what is machine
learning what is good learning at the
end I'm going to tell you how a
full-stack programmer like me that
doesn't like math and a dozen really
like calculus in all that can get
started working with artificial
intelligence and machine learning
ai ai is divided in two categories
narrow AI in general area
Hollywood and Netflix and all the movies
are in general AI general AI is machines
that do everything that humans do and
better that can do a general purpose AI
that can do anything so it can talk it
can learn to play games it can
communicate it can make a judgment it
can just be exactly like a human in
varies general AI right now in the world
in the industry we are in a narrow AI
narrow AI are machines that can only do
one thing and one thing very well where
the focus of the machine is narrow
the applications are narrow the machine
can do one thing well and one thing only
an example of narrow AI would be for
example the Facebook AI at finding out
faces in photos but that's it this AI is
not able to learn how to find out dogs
in photos because is narrow is general
is narrow AI it can only do one thing
well and one thing only
that's what we are right now but now we
need to understand how we teach those
hey guys here is where machine learning
is the way to accomplish a a I so how
the machines learn there are many
categories of machine learning but the
most famous ones are to
on supervised learning and supervised
learning let's say that we are going to
make an application that detects if a
food is a hot dog or not a hot dog if we
did it in a supervised way what we will
do is that we will label what a hot dog
is okay a hot dog is a sausage a hot dog
is long a hot dog has some sauce on top
a hot dog has is between a bun that is a
label we're going to label what a hot
dog is we're going to tell the Machine
what a hot dog is right and then we are
going to get millions of photos of any
kind of food we're going to put that
into the machine in the machine based in
our labels the machine is going to say
ok this photo has 60% chance of being a
hot dog so the machine is not thinking
the machine is just telling us in a
probability way with statistics and
mathematics it just train us this has
95% chance of being a hot dog based on
the labels that the humans gave to the
machine one example of supervised
machine learning will be for example a
music recommendation system the user US
will label the songs a good night so we
will tell the Machine these are the snow
that I enjoy this is the ton of beat
that I enjoy this is the kind of artists
that I like next time a new song comes
the Machine now has labeled data into
what is a song that Nikolas likes and
then you will know if Nikolas has a 90%
chance of liking this new song that's
coming up that is supervised learning
humans label the data now in
unsupervised learning the humans do not
label the data so for example to do this
hot dog app what we are going to do is
that we are going to give to the Machine
millions of photos of only hot dogs
we're going to give that to the Machine
we're gonna give the machine any leg
and we are going to let the Machine by
itself figure out a label that makes a
hot dog so when you're going to tell any
description of a hot dog we're just
gonna give the Machine a lot of hot dog
photos in the machine we'll figure out
by itself after a lot of time and a lot
of processing power and a lot a lot of
data all right now of course I know this
is just a very simple explanation if you
want this if you like this topic we can
talk more about it in super in future
videos but now I need to move on to the
last topic which is learning deep
learning is just a way to accomplish
machine learning machine learning is a
way to accomplish a deep learning is
called deep learning because it makes
use of something called neural networks
very smart scientists very smart
mathematicians and computer scientists
and all that they came up with this
algorithm that works like a brain you
need a lot of data to train that and you
need a lot of processing power because
it's a very long and computer intensive
process but that's it deep learning is a
way to accomplish machine learning
machine learning is a way to accomplish
AI
all right now deep learning is being
used by companies for example like
Google or Google or Tesla for example
because they can process and have
massive amounts of data and they have
massive amounts of money so how does a
full-stack programmer come up and start
working with machine learning and deep
learning well if you want to get started
in machine learning you have to learn
Python that is like the best way to get
started if you know Python then you can
move on and look into something called
tensorflow
thankfully you don't have to do all
these things by yourself manually you
don't have to create a neural networks
by OSHA the community has already built
tons and tons of things the most popular
framework for artificial intelligence is
called tensor flow tensor flow is in
JavaScript and Python so those two
languages are super super easy to do get
start to do it and you can get started
tomorrow if you wanted to also there is
this thing called brain jail on brain
j/s they already have neural net
works deep learning algorithms
activation functions I'll on the
things already done for you to work with
deep learning and no GS so if you ask me
it's an amazing thing like I said the
community has already built so many
things so if you're scared of math
calculation on that you can go and start
playing around with tensorflow
or with brain shaders and that will just
give you an introduction of what is
machine learning without having to take
care of all the math in the calculus
Python and JavaScript those two
languages are gonna be big big big big
on machine learning I think Python
already is it's a massive in JavaScript
is a start in there because it's on the
web thank you for watching I hope that
you enjoyed this video let me know what
you think let me know in the comments
just keep in mind that this concept is
for newbies and I'm not trying to be
super correct and specific in all the
things I say so if you think actually
that was wrong you just remember that
I'm just trying to explain this into the
easiest terms icon let me know what you
think leave a like leave a comment
subscribe share to your friends and as
always don't forget to eat kimchi bye
bye